本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
パルス暦３２０年　冬
The era of Parsis, winter 320 years.
Army Parsis headed Narsusom, destroyed army Rajendra,
ナルサス率いるパルス軍は
国境に侵入したシンドゥラ国第二王子　ラジェンドラの軍を打ち破った
the second prince of the kingdom sindoor, Parsis crossed the border.
アルスラーンは　捕虜となってペシャワールに引っ立てられた
Rajendra resulted in Peshavard as a prisoner,
ラジェンドラを客として迎え入れ　同盟を結んだ
but Arslan received him as a guest, and a covenant with him.
ここに　両軍はシンドゥラ国第一王子　ガーデーヴィ打倒のため
Now the two armies
We went across the border in a military campaign,
国境を越えた遠征へと旅立った
to overthrow Gadevi, Crown Prince of the Kingdom of sindoor.
この　この
Take that!
So!
The second prince of the kingdom sindoor, Rajendra
アルスラーン殿
Prince Lions!
いや　パルス兵の強さ　実に見事だ
Yes, the power of the soldiers Parsis really amazing.
ラジェンドラ殿
Prince Rajendra.
特にダリューン卿の武勇には目をみはったぞ
Particularly striking prowess of Mr. Daryuna.
私には過ぎた仲間たちです
I do not deserve such comrades.
No no. Such capable people
いやいや　彼らほどの者を従えられるのはアルスラーン殿の器ゆえよ
just right for you, Prince Arslan.
Mr. Kisvard stayed to defend the fortress Peshavard,
ペシャワールの守りに残っているキシュワード卿の技も見てみたかった
but I would like to see and it in fact.
知っておるぞ　双刀将軍の名は
I know the nickname of General two swords.
ナルサス
Narsus, I can not bring myself to trust him.
どうも俺はあの男を信用できん
むしろ　俺はヤツがどういう策を巡らせてくるか　待ちかねているよ
Anyway, I would wait to see what he has prepared us.
Explorer Army Parsis from the kingdom sindoor, Jaswant
ジャスワントよ
Jaswant.
お前はラジェンドラの軍に潜伏せよ
You're going undercover army Rajendra.
ははっ
Hereditary Grand Vizier kingdom sindoor, Mahendra
危険な役割だが　なんとしてもヤツらの進軍を阻止するのだ
This is a dangerous mission,
but you have to stop them at all costs.
Your Excellency, you are to me as a father.
宰相閣下は　私にとって父も同然でございます
この命に代えても
I'll put a life if necessary.
kaze ga zawameki kudaketa kimochi
Quiet wind awakens emotions and broken,
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
misukashi teru you de furueta yo
I see through everything and I shiver.
michita tsuki no hi touboe no inochi
In the sky a full moon, and the city comes howling:
片源
Rei
时间轴
钦钦&框框
压制
久嘉
Coolkid
mada oite kanaide yo
"Please do not throw until we have!"
bokura torikaeseru ka na iro tsuki no sora
Will we return to the old sky, painted in the colors?
hokori mamire no yume mai agete
Rise in the dance vortex hourglass Sci,
kobushi wo nigittanara
to be clamped in their fists.
ima hashire hashire tsuji kaze ni natte
Now run forward, run forward, and stand by the whirlwind,
rettou zetsubou issai fukitobashite iku
feelings of hopelessness and despair of sour cream on the way.
oikakenakya saigo no tobira
Clears the currently last track.
nando chittatte dai gyakuten
Let all break, we will rise again,
kono goe ga shagare tatte inorinouta todoketai yo
even a hoarse voice will sing songs and prayers.
tarinai bokura de shinji teta sekai wo ubaetara
Even insignificant, as we will be able to capture the whole world in which to believe.
madamada madamada make rarenai
We have still not yet been defeated!
Chapter XV
パルス暦３２１年
The era of Parsis, 321 a year.
Arslan met the new year on the western wastelands sindoor.
その年明けをアルスラーンはシンドゥラ国西方の広野で迎えた
パルス式に新年の儀式が行われ　彼は国王の代理としての役割を果たした
New Year's ritual was held in the tradition of Parsis,
and the guy has fulfilled its role as regent.
アルスラーン　アルスラーン
Lions! Lions!
天上に輝く星　神々の寵児よ
Shining star of heaven, beloved of the gods,
his wisdom and power
御身の智と力によりて
bring peace to the kingdom and its people!
国と民とに平安をもたらされんことを
ああ　俺には宴の酒もまったく意味がない
Even the wine banquet does not affect me.
I was able to intoxicate only your beauty, Mrs Farangis.
ファランギース殿の美貌のみが俺を酔わせることができる
わしは悪酔いしそうじゃ　お主と話してるとな
It seems to me, if after our conversation will be a hangover.
Here, Narsus!
はい　ナルサス
No, do not worry about me.
いや　俺に構うことはない
いいから
Come on, "ah-ah-ah!"
ナルサス様が困っているだろう
You interfere with Mr. Narsusu.
Elam, it is none of your business.
エラムには関係ないでしょ
Guys...
二人とも…
The best tactics can not cope with the children.
天下随一の策士が子供相手に形なしだな
Welcome back, Azrael.
おかえり　アズライール
ラジェンドラ殿
Prince Rajendra ...
アルスラーン殿　新年の挨拶に来た
Prince Arslan came to congratulate you on the new year.
わざわざ　ありがとうございます
Thank you for coming.
パルスの兵士たちも大いに英気を養っているようで何より
And also like to see,
Parsis have soldiers recover.
ところで　我が友にして心の兄弟たるアルスラーン殿
By the way, my friend and brother in spirit, Prince Arslan,
I would like to talk to you.
相談があるのだが
About what?
なんでしょうか
ラジェンドラの兵と我々が別の道筋を行き
Soldiers Rajendra our go their separate ways
二方向から　ガーデーヴィを挟み撃ちにすると
and hit the Gadevi on both sides.
Yes, this strategy offered the prince Rajendra,
ラジェンドラ殿が提案してきた作戦だが…
どう思う
as you?
お断りなさるべきです
I would refuse.
あの男　信用すべきではありません
And I am of the same opinion.
俺もそう思いますね
あの王子様　きっと俺たちを囮に使うつもりですよ
This prince probably conceived to make us the bait.
ファランギース殿も同じお考えでは
Ms. Farangis, you also think so?
不愉快なことじゃがな
Yes, though with reluctance.
我らがガーデーヴィの主力とぶつかれば
If we are faced with the shock group Gadevi,
Whatever conceived Rajendra, it is to be on hand.
ラジェンドラは何をするにも都合がよいじゃろうな
I did and was afraid.
やはりそう思うか
ナルサスの考えを聞きたい
I want to hear your opinion, Narsus.
まず　殿下にお祝い申し上げます
First, congratulations, Prince.
殿下の部下に　どうやら阿呆は一人もおりませぬようですので
It turns out that among your followers are no fools.
皆の考えるとおり
As you think,
ラジェンドラ王子の真意は我々を囮として利用することにあります
Prince Rajendra intends to use us as bait.
ですが　その提案　ご承諾なさいませ
However, you should agree to his plan.
それはなぜだ
Why?
確かにラジェンドラ王子は信用できません
Granted, the prince Rajendra can not be trusted.
しかし　ならばむしろ距離を置いて行動した方がよろしい
But in this case we should cooperate with them in the distance.
なるほど
Clear.
ただし　条件をお付けください
Only on a few conditions.
糧食　それを運搬する牛馬　地図　信用のおける案内人
Supplies, oxen for their transportation,
maps and guide you can trust.
Tell me, what are your requirements.
それらを要求なさいませ
Two days later,
ラジェンドラ王子より遣わされました
I sent Prince Rajendra.
ジャスワントと申します
My name is Jaswant.
ウライユールへの案内を務めさせていただきます
I would be honored to serve you a guide to Uraiyura.
Jaswant, huh? I am counting on you.
ジャスワントか　よろしく頼む
Yes. Then I will go forth to lead your army.
はい
それでは　これより私が隊の先頭を務めさせていただきます
Poisonous snake.
毒蛇でございます　お気をつけください
Be careful.
この辺りは冬でもこういった生き物が一部活動しております
On these lands, some animals even in winter capacity.
Yes, thanks.
ありがとう
失礼いたしました　それでは後ほど
Forgive the intrusion.
See you later.
糧食運搬隊　集まれ
Convoy gathered!
随分な挨拶ですね　どなたですか
A great way to welcome. Who are you?
悪いな　手が滑っちまった
I'm sorry, hand she jerked.
俺はギーヴ
I Giev. And who are you?
あんた　何者だ
私は使いの案内人です
Conductor sent to you.
どうだろうな
Interesting.
やっぱりただ者じゃないだろ
I knew it, you're not just a conductor.
I apologize.
失礼します
かなりの腕だぞ　あの男
He has good skills.
ラジェンドラめ　まさか殿下に危害を…
That's the same Rajendra ...
He planned to harm the prince?
It's possible.
ありうるかもな
fortress Gujarat
殿下　あれがグジャラート城塞です
Prince, a fortress of Gujarat.
これを落とす方法はいくらでもございますが
are several ways to her,
あまり時間をかけてはいられません
but we should not linger here.
What do we do?
では　どうするのだ
ひとまず　使者を送ろうと思います
To begin, I would have sent a messenger.
戦わずに通過できる可能性を探りましょう
See if there is a chance to go without a fight.
見て　すてき
城司ゴーヴィン様　ご入場
Lt. Col. fortress Gujarat kingdom sindoor, Taara
Enters Mr. Gauvin commander of the fortress.
The commander of the fortress of the kingdom of Gujarat sindoor, Gauvin
パルス軍の使者か
Envoys of Parsis army?
はい　私はギーヴ
Yes. I Giev.
ジャスワントと申します
My name is Jaswant.
用件は
What do you need?
我々との休戦に応じ　パルス軍の通過を許可していただきたい
We would like to ask you
permission to pass Parsis army.
正気か
You're crazy?
そのようなことをしては　ガーデーヴィ様に申し開きできん
If I give consent,
that can not justify their actions before the Prince Gadevi.
Of course, not for a simple thank you.
もちろん　タダとは言わぬ
ラジェンドラ王子が国王になった暁には
As soon as the prince Rajendra ascend to the throne,
あなた方を厚く遇すると仰せになっている
He said that generously thank you.
地位にせよ領地にせよ　望む全てを与えようと
Whether it is the title of the land or,
He will provide all that you wish.
What do you think?
いかがかな
即答はできん
I can not answer immediately.
I see.
結構　明日までお待ちいたしましょう
We'll wait until tomorrow.
よい返事を期待しております
We look forward to a positive response.
宴席を用意いたしました
We have prepared a banquet for you.
これ　使者殿らのおもてなしを
Next, entertain messengers.
パルスの使者様　こちらへ
Mr. Envoy Parsis, here.
We have prepared the best wine.
最上のぶどう酒を用意しております
無論　あなた方が傍らでついでくれるのであろう
And of course, you, ladies, sit with me, and will pour it?
もちろんでございます
Of course, we will.
さあ　どうぞ
Come on, here.
No, I ...
Here, please.
こちらへどうぞ
Night long. I have fun while you have a chance.
夜は長い　ゆっくり楽しもう
そうおっしゃらずに
Do not say that.
やめろ
So, what do we do?
さて　どうする
パルスがラジェンドラに肩入れするとなれば
If Parsa teamed with Rajendra,
he has the advantage in the battle for the throne.
王位争いはヤツが有利　ならば…
Then...
じゃが　もしそうならなかったら　我らは反逆者だ
But if they will not work, we will be traitors.
But now with the army to fight Parsis ...
しかし　パルス軍と今やり合うのは…
失礼します
I apologize.
Oh, sir messenger, something happened?
これはこれは　使者殿　いかがなされた
両将軍にお話があります
I wanted something to discuss with your generals.
But first take a look at it.
その前に　まずこれを
This signature, Mr. Mahendra, advisor to Prince Gadevi!
これはガーデーヴィ様の参謀　マヘーンドラ様の署名
お主　何者だ
Who are you?!
私はマヘーンドラ様の部下
I submit to Mr. Mahendra.
ラジェンドラとパルスの進軍を阻止するよう仰せつかっている者です
I was asked to stop the invasion and Rajendra Parsa.
Generals, it is said that this Giev, complete nonsense.
両将軍　あのギーブなる者が言っていることは全くのデタラメです
What?!
何
私に考えがあります
I have a guess.
開城を求める使者は囮
The envoys sent to ask permission - bait.
パルス軍の作戦は　あなた方が休戦の申し入れに気を取られている隙に
Army Parsis conceived
petition distract you and take advantage of this time,
to pass the fortress of Gujarat.
グジャラート城を通過してしまうことです
なんじゃと
What?!
そのような謀り事を
They went on a trick! ..
そうと分かれば　ギーヴとかいう食わせ者を血祭りに挙げ
Once we know this,
I want to see blood shed this balabolov Gieva
and hang his body at the gates!
城門にさらしてくれよう
お待ちください
Wait.
パルス軍は精強です
Parsis Army strong.
With them it is better not to engage in battle.
まともにやり合うのは避けた方がいい
では　どうしたら…
What then?
パルスの裏をかくのです
We deal wisely Pars.
パルス軍の隊列は主力の騎兵が先に立ち　糧食隊はいちばん後ろです
Parsis army convoy
lead riders, its main strength.
A detachment of provisions at the end.
これを狙うべきです
On them we will strike.
食料がなければ　それ以上進軍することはできない
Without provisions, they can not go far.
私の合図で　パルス軍を後方から襲撃してください
At my signal, you attack an army Parsis from the rear.
こんなときでも単独行動とは　寂しい人生だな
Alone, there's something you do? It must be lonely to you is.
Mr. Giev.
ギーヴ殿
油断も隙もない
You can not lose vigilance.
黒猫さんよ　発火筒より先に　あんたの尻尾に火がついてるみたいだぜ
Black cat,
I think your tail on fire faster than this flare.
俺の素性を見抜いていたのか
So, you've already opened.
我らが軍師殿は物が見え過ぎる御仁でな
Our master tactician calculates everything in advance.
ジャスワントの合図はまだか
Jaswant has not yet been signaled?
このままでは　パルス軍が城を通過してしまう
At this rate, Parsis army held our fortress!
We can not wait any longer!
これ以上は待てん
襲撃だ
In the attack!
食料を奪い尽くせ
Pick up all the provisions!
敵襲
Attack!
りょ…糧食隊ではない
Uh, this is not a detachment of provisions!
はめられ…
Obma us ...
ターラ
Taara!
ゴーヴィン様
Mr. Gauvin!
... this should not have been ...
こんな…はずでは…
You go around!
回り込め
パルスの小僧
Parsiansky kid!
そこを動くな
Our places!
Prince!
殿下
ゴーヴィン様が死んだ
Mr. Gauvin is dead!
O-retreat!
た…退却だ
終わりましたな
All over.
It looks like a fortress commander dead.
城司は死んだようだ
勝敗はついた
So, the battle was over.
諦めろ
前は手を抜いていたのか
You then fought not at full strength?
あんなところで本気出すわけないだろ
I will never give in at this time.
ギーヴ
Giev!
ジャスワント
Jaswant.
初めから裏切るつもりだったのか
You from the beginning I have betrayed?
裏切る？　それは違うな
Betrayed? You are wrong.
俺はシンドゥラ人だ
I sindurianets!
初めからシンドゥラの宰相閣下の命に従い　ただ忠誠を尽くしただけだ
From the beginning I was following orders of Grand Vizier sindoor
and only carried the faithful service!
ガーデーヴィ殿下のためか
Prince Gadevi?
違う　俺が忠誠を尽くすのは　我が父に等しい宰相マヘーンドラ様のみ
No.
I faithfully serve
Mr. Grand Vizier Mahendra, who was like a father to me.
殿下　いつまでも裏切り者の舌を回らせておく必要はありません
Prince,
there is no need to chat with this traitor.
待ってくれ　ギーヴ
Wait, Giev. Let me even talk to him.
もう少し話をさせてくれ
What do you mean, you were like a father?
その父に等しいとはどういうことだ
俺は自分の父親が誰であるのか知らぬ
I do not know his real father.
孤児であった俺を育ててくれたのがマヘーンドラ様だった
I was an orphan, and Mr. Mahendra brought me up.
それだけのことだ
That's all.
You do not know their parents?
自分の親を知らないのか
Come on, get it over with me!
さあ　このうえは速やかに俺の命を絶て
では　望みどおり
Well, as you wish ...
Wait.
待ってくれ
Please release him.
この者を解放してやってくれ
そうおっしゃると思いました
I thought you'd say that.
殿下の仰せとあらば　剣を引きますが
Once that is your order, I'll take your sword,
ですが　どうか後日　後悔なさらぬよう
Only then do not regret this decision.
正直　お甘いと思いますが…
I believe you are too lenient,
よろしいでしょう　私どもの力が及ばぬほどの害にはならないと存じます
but okay.
I think no matter what the consequences,
we will be able to cope with them.
Thank Narsus.
ありがとう　ナルサス
ナルサスの料理は私が作る
I make dinner Narsusu.
いいえ　私が
No, I do.
私はナルサス様の好みを知り尽くしているし　栄養の管理も完璧だ
I am well aware of Mr Narsusa tastes
and blends perfectly with their nutritional needs.
ナルサスだって　女の子から作ってもらった方がうれしいでしょう
Even Narsus be happy if she will cook for him.
It is true Narsus?
ねえ　ナルサス
ナルサス様
Mr. Narsus.
Y-yes. Okay, then I'll eat all that you are both ready.
では　二人が作った料理　両方食べよう
それでいいだろう
It'll do?
はい　では　すぐに夕食の支度を…
Yes! Then I now cook dinner for you.
Now I cook!
してくるから
I'm sure Mr. Narsus just say that one of my cooking it enough.
すぐにナルサス様は私の料理だけでいいとおっしゃるはずだ
I will say the same thing!
それは私のセリフ
見ていたのか
Saw?
ああ　なかなか面白かったぞ
Yes. And it's pretty funny.
Do not look like that.
まあ　そうにらむな
Yeah. Elam in situations like such a child.
まったく　エラムもまだまだ子供なところがある
Know Narsus,
なあ　ナルサス
将来アルスラーン殿下が国王となり　エラムがそれを補佐する
Prince Arslan in the future will be king
and Elam will be his advisor.
そうすれば　よい政事が行えるのではないか
Do you think this will provide a good grip?
そうだな　遅くても１０年先にはそうなってほしいものだ
Yes.
At least, I hope it will happen in ten years.
殿下はおそらくアンドラゴラス王の子ではなく　パルス王家の血を引いていない
Prince did not seem son Andragorasa
and not from the royal line Parsis.
Yes.
殿下もそのことにお気付きだろう
Prince probably also guessed.
だが俺は　パルス国のためにはやはりあの方こそが王となるべきだと思う
But I do not care, I think that for the benefit of the most Parsis
he should become king.
俺も同じだ
I agree.
Royal capital Uraiyur Kingdom sindoor
たった３日でグジャラートが落ちただと
Gujarat has fallen for some three days ?!
Crown Prince sindoor, Gadevi
Parsis army so powerful?
これがパルス軍の力か
Prince Gadevi, I think it's time to go already.
ガーデーヴィ様　もはや我らから打って出るべきでしょう
パルスとラジェンドラの兵を合わせても　まだ我々の兵力が勝っております
Even the combined forces of the Parsis and Rajendra
inferior in the number of our army.
加えて我らには戦象部隊があります
In addition, we have war elephants.
ああ…　そうか　そうだな
Exactly. You're right.
Andragoras even he failed to win the war with elephants.
戦象部隊にはあのアンドラゴラスでさえ勝てなかったのだ
And the punk Arslan ...
アルスラーンとかいう小僧ごとき…
YakuSub Studio
kimi ga deatta kokoro wa kitto
All the souls that you could meet on the way,
translation Mu_Cool
hitotsu datte machigai janai
certainly it was pure and innocent,
Editorial Mu_Cool
onaji yume wo daite
We kept the same dream.
Making Weekend
michi wo tagaeta hito wo omotta
People walking different paths,
nozarashi no akogare wo kakagete susumu kouya
killed all my hopes and desires revive again.
hohoemi mo sono namida mo
Smile on his face, tears running down her cheeks,
koko ni suteteyukenai kara
If you want to go ahead, they should not be forgotten.
kage wo daite shiroku takaku
Covered by the shadow of the summer, so white and immense,
namonaki boku to kimi no hata
our with you nameless flag flies.
mada hatenaku tsudzuku kono mich ino kanata ni
There, on the road, which extends an endless path,
tatta hitotsu no hikari wo sen no kokoro ni
There is one bright light, and with it a thousand souls.
miageru sora wo shinjiteru
Believe in the sky above his head,
michibiku hoshi wo higashi no takami ni sashishimesu yo
there putevodnaâ our star in the east, ee do not engage.
yume wa kono te de kanaeru
And their cherished dream in flesh forces.
ジャスワントは自分の親を知らぬと言った
Jaswant said that he does not know his parents.
私も自分が誰の子なのか分からぬ
I myself do not know whose son I am.
Prince, winter nights are cold, you undermine health.
殿下
冬の夜風はお体に障ります
そろそろお休みになられては
Maybe go down to the room?
ダリューン
Darjun.
Who am i?
私は一体何者なんだろう
I...
私は王家の子ではな…
not royal ...
I Daryun, I know who you are, Prince.
殿下のご正体はこのダリューンが存じております
ダリューン…
Darjun ...
For me, Daryuna you - my lord and dearest people.
殿下はこのダリューンにとって　何よりも大事な主君でいらっしゃいます
That's enough, Prince?
それではいけませんか　殿下
ありがとう　ダリューン
Thank Daryun.
無傷無敵の戦象部隊は　大地を鳴動させながら
From neuyazvimыh and nepobedimыh
elephants shakes the earth,
ついに　パルス軍に襲いかかっていった
when they moved to the army Parsis.
次回　落日悲歌
Next time:. "Elegy of the setting sun"
Chapter XVI
少年は　そして王となる
And so the guy would be King.